CURRICULUM VITAE

PERSONAL SUMMARY

An analytically minded, skilled Graduate of Computer Science, who enjoys coding, is reliable and dependable, and has 16 years of experience in Database Management and Application Development, a certified Python Developer (PCAP), with basic Computer Networking skills and knowledge of Linux System Administration.

Reliable and dependable, can work effectively as an individual as well as part of teams. Currently seeking Junior Software Developer, Junior DevOps, Junior Python Developer, and Junior Java Developer roles. Keen to further develop skills.

KEY SKILLS

- Python 3 (PCAP certified), C#, and Java programming
- Linux (LPI certified Linux Essentials Professional Developer)
- HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, SQL, PostgresSQL, PHP, React, REST APIs, ExpressJS, NodeJS, TDD, GitHub
- FullStack Engineering (PERN)
- Computer Networking skills
- Advanced Excel ability, Data Analysis with Excel
- Competent and proficient user of MS Office and cloud storage
- Good organisational skills
- High-level of attention to detail

EDUCATION	Q_{τ} TID A IN	יאווו
EDUCATION	α I NAIIN	UIII

Ahmadu Bello University, Zaria, NG

IJMB A' Levels: Mathematics, Geography & Physics

EDUCATION & TRAINING	
FullStack Engineer	Nov 2021 – Jan 2023
IT Career Switch, UK	
Certified in Linux Essentials	Sep 2021 – Nov 2021
The Linux Professional Institute with CISCO Network Academy	
Certified Associate Python Programmer	Mar 2021 – Aug 2021
The Python Institute with CISCO Network Academy	Mai 2021 – Aug 2021
Post-graduate Certificate in Educational Studies	2018 – 2019
Birmingham City University, UK	
Certified Enterprise Application Developer & Solutions Architect On Sun Java.	2009 – 2010
National Institute for Information Technology, NG	
MSc Computer Science	1993 – 1995
Abubakar Tafawa Balewa University, Bauchi, NG	1993 – 1993
Ababakai Talawa balewa Oliivelsity, badolii, 110	
BSc Maths-with-Computer Science	1983 – 1987

1982 - 1983

•	Certification in Linux Essentials (Linux Professional Institute)	Dec 2021
•	Certified Associate Python Programmer (The Python Institute)	Sep 2021
•	Computer Networking – Discovering Computer Networks (The Open University)	Aug 2021
•	Excel for Data Analysis (Insight Edge)	Apr 2021
•	Excel Crash Course Certificate (Corporate Finance Institute)	Feb 2020
•	Beginner to PROject Management Certificate (365 Careers)	Dec 2019
•	Customer Service Essentials (Rethink Mental Illness; L & D Service)	Mar 2018
•	ECDL (IT Skills & Improving Productivity) Level 2 (Learndirect)	Jun 2015
•	Enterprise Application Developer & Solutions Architect on Sun Java (NIIT)	Jun 2010

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cyber Technical Assistant

National Grid

Warwick/Hybrid, UK Aug 2022 – Date

- Supporting the Cyber Optel Manager with administration of Cyber operations
- Supporting the Cyber Portfolio Leads with financial administration tasks
- · Requisitioning and receipting of purchase orders
- Booking deliveries, site surveys, co-ordination meetings and installation works
- Attending planning, co-ordination, and financial review meetings

Key achievements:

 Developed a procedure for the team, to simplify the process of managing Purchase Orders and recording financial transactions, to facilitate ready access to financial data and both timely and accurate financial reporting.

Virtual Data Administrator

Hamitaf Ltd.

Remote, UK Oct 2019 – Feb 2021

Offered freelance online data administrative services, including:

- Data Analysis with Excel
- Collation of business performance data from various sources
- Data processing and report generation
- Spreadsheet creation and maintenance of databases
- General Administration (Data Entry, Word Processing, Email Inbox Management)

Key achievements:

Completed Project Management and Advanced Excel courses in this period

Administrator

Rethink Mental Illness, Advice & Information Service

Birmingham, UK Apr 2016 - Aug 2018

- Compiled and collated statistical data on the Service's activities, performed analysis on the data, updated relevant databases and generated monthly and annual reports
- Supported the Service Manager, Head of Service, and a team of Advisers with administrative and financial management tasks
- Initiated and responded to client communication. Ensured a high quality and prompt response to all enquiries.
- Trained new team members on how to use certain systems in the Service

Key achievements:

 Revamped the Information Reviewers Excel database, and the method of storing information in it, reducing the time taken for selection of information reviewers from the database, by about 75%

Voluntary Support Roles In Administration/Customer Service

DWP, EFA Foundation, Green Lane Community Centre, UK

Sep 2014 – Oct 2015

- Processed customer survey data
- Supported a team of 20 job advisers in delivering their services to customers, handled phone calls.
- Created, updated, and maintained Excel databases
- Performed online research and general administrative duties
- Received payments from customers and handled book-keeping of finances
- Supported in organising fundraising activities

Key achievements:

Re-organised digital filing systems, and improved on processes

Assistant Chief Systems Analyst

University of Lagos, NG

May 1998 - Sep 2014

- Developed in-house database management software.
- Created and maintained databases, ensuring the integrity of their content
- Managed data processing department: processed semester examinations, staff training tests and some entrance examination results. Ensured jobs were processed accurately and within timescales. Utilised high level of attention to detail
- Supervised daily operations and handled the finances. Purchased all office supplies and maintained all office resources, liaised with suppliers and maintenance personnel, both external and internal
- Managed team of data processing staff. Catered for their welfare and progression
- Provided administrative and IT support to other teams and colleagues at different levels. Liaised with staff in other departments across the University

Key achievements:

 Simplified administrative processes with software solutions, creating ease of work and reduced taskcompletion times by up to 50%

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

Customer Service OfficerOct 2019 – Dec 2019Senior Programmer/Part-time Lecturer/Mathematics TutorJul 1992 – Nov 1997Lecturer III (Mathematics)Jan 1989 – Jul 1992Youth Corp memberAug 1987 – Aug 1988

HOBBIES & EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Reading, Analytical Puzzles, Digital games, Baking, Wool craft, Sewing, Language learning